Michael Chrupcala

Software Engineer

michael.chrupcala@gmail.com | (609) 781-0496 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelchrupcala | 87 Bergen Street, Brooklyn NY 11201

Professional Summary

Creative software engineer with 5 years of experience shipping modern web applications, known for showing leadership while creating gorgeous user interfaces and UX. Seeking a frontend, full-stack or backend role to leverage my skills with React, JavaScript, TypeScript, AWS, and other technologies.

Work Experience

Software Engineer

Art Blocks | Dec 2021 - Aug 2024 | Remote

\$1B+ in revenue in 2021. The premier publisher of contemporary, generative NFT art.

- Built an encrypted purchase flow for art auctions, resulting in 42,000+ users claiming NFTs
- Saved \$255,000 of engineering time over 5 years by creating a cloud-based request tracking pipeline
- Developed a digital art renderer, so 40k art collectors could capture 300k+ NFTs as image/video files
- Automated the HD processing of 150k+ images via Python script, improving image quality by 211%
- Recognized as culture leader while remote. Built morale-boosting programs, DJ'd all-hands meetings
- Collaborated with designers cross-functionally to build and successfully launch 6 major products

Lead Frontend Developer

Distributed Towns | Mar 2021 - Dec 2021 | Remote

DAO Analytics platform, enabling wallet authorization & communication for decentralized communities.

- Rebuilt two websites from scratch, improving codebase flexibility, and reducing code by 40%
- Won top prizes in global hackathons (Encode, HackMoney). Finished Consensys' Tachyon accelerator
- Wrote a React open-source website for DAO wallet analytics, integrated with Solidity smart contracts

Software Engineer

CVS Health | June 2020 – June 2021 | Remote

- Completed an Excel extractor report to ingest manufacturer data for users, while training a new hire
- Built a microservice to transform user data and send to external REST API for Azure computation
- Wrote and presented lectures on GraphQL APIs, blockchains & Web3 to an audience of 60+ engineers

Education

2015 - BM in Music Business from New York University, NY

Skills

JavaScript | TypeScript | React | NextJS | NodeJS | AWS | Python | Tailwind | HTML | CSS | GitHub